reedelsevier.com 2012-09-15

# Reed Elsevier website privacy and cookie policy

The following statement explains our policy regarding the personal information we collect about you as you visit our website, [www.reedelsevier.com](http://www.reedelsevier.com/).   Individual business enterprises of the Reed Elsevier family of companies (Elsevier, LexisNexis Risk Solutions, LexisNexis Legal & Professional, Reed Exhibitions and Reed Business Information) maintain separate privacy policies tailored to their specific products and services. 

This statement was last updated on 25 May 2012

 **1\. What Personal Information is Collected?**  
Reed Elsevier collects personal information at this website (such as name, email address, phone number) when you submit it to us for certain products and services such as email alerts, to provide feedback or when you create an account on our Career page.    
We also collect information about your computer browser when you interact with our online services, including the computer’s IP address, browser type, operating system, and the web pages you visit.  If you access our website from a mobile or other device, we may collect a unique device identifier contained in that device. This information allows us to display or format relevant content and services for that device. 

**2.   Information We May Share**  
We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal information about our website visitors, except as described here.  We may share information provided by our website with our corporate affiliates and with business partners who we have retained to perform services on our behalf.  We may also share your information with other organisations for the purpose of fraud prevention or the detection of fraud.[ When we share your information in this way,  we ensure that it is protected in accordance with this policy.  In addition, we may disclose information about you: (a) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, or (b) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials.  
In the event we sell or transfer a portion of our business, we may sell or share any information we have about you as part of our business or assets.  Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided through this web site in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

**3\. Access and Correction**  
Reed Elsevier wants to ensure that any personal information you provide through this website remains accurate.  At your request, we will inform you of the information we hold about you that was collected from this website.  If you require changes to such personal information, please send an email to: [Privacy.Policy@ReedElsevier.com](mailto:Privacy.Policy@ReedElsevier.com).

You may request details of the data we hold about you in accordance with data protection laws.  Please write to our customer services team at: 

**Postal Address:**     
Reed Elsevier  
Attn: Privacy Policy Enquiry  
1-3 Strand  
London    
WC2N 5JR

**4\. Direct Marketing and User Surveys**   
As Reed Elsevier’s services expand, there may be more opportunities to enhance the services provided to you. Periodically, we may send you details of other services and products that may be of interest to you and offer you the opportunity to subscribe to them.  We may also offer you the opportunity to participate in surveys, carried out by Reed Elsevier or its agents.  Reed Elsevier will keep a record of information provided by you. Please note that any information you provide will only be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  If you do not wish to receive direct marketing materials, you may opt out by sending an email to [Privacy.Policy@ReedElsevier.com](mailto:Privacy.Policy@ReedElsevier.com)

 **5.   International Transfer of Information**  
We may transfer the personal information we collect on this site to other countries where we do business, but we will do so only for the purposes described above.  When we transfer your information to other countries, we will take steps to ensure the same level of protection for that information as is required within Europe. 

**6.   Children's Privacy **  
This website is not directed to children under the age of 18, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 18 on this website. 

**7.   How We Safeguard Personal Information **  
We have security systems intended to ensure the availability, confidentiality and integrity of your information.  This includes multi-layered systems for information technology, information security and physical security.  We use industry-standard access control software and methods that include vulnerability analysis, rigorous intrusion detection systems and regular penetration testing.  Our information and system security professionals continuously refine these processes as threats evolve.

 **8.   Cookies**  
This website employs a common technology called cookies.  A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to a specific directory for the browser on your computer or mobile device so that the website can remember who you are between visits.  
The cookies used on this website are Performance Cookies.  These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages.  These cookies do not collect information that identifies a visitor.  All information that these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous.  It is only used to improve how the website works.  We use Google Analytics and SharePoint SP Session Guide for this purpose.  In addition, we use a MediaMind cookie to facilitate the delivery of video presentations that are accessed through our website.

By using this website, you agree that we can place Performance Cookies cookies on your device.   
To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across our website for the limited purposes set forth above, visit <http://tools.google/dopage/gaoptout>.  For more information about MediaMind, go to <http://www.mediamind.com/privacy-policy>.  You also have the ability to accept or decline cookies generally by modifying the settings in your web browser.  There are a number of ways to manage cookies. The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new browser cookie, and how to disable existing browser cookies. 

**9.   How to Contact Reed Elsevier about Your Personal Information  
**Email address: [Privacy.Policy@ReedElsevier.com](mailto:Privacy.Policy@ReedElsevier.com)

Postal Address:    
Reed Elsevier  
Attn: Privacy Policy Enquiry  
1-3 Strand  
London    
WC2N 5JR

**10.   Links  
**We provide links to other websites for your convenience and information.. Please be aware that Reed Elsevier is not responsible for the privacy practices of any third party sites.  Therefore, we encourage our users to read the privacy statement of those third party sites that collect personally identifiable information. This Privacy Statement applies solely to information collected by this website.

**11.   Changes to the Privacy Statement**   
As new products and services are offered or as existing products and services are improved, we may need to change our Privacy Policy.  We will post the changes here.  Where the changes are significant, we may also email our registered visitors with the new details.  Where required by law, will we obtain your consent to make these changes.
